Hello everyone and welcome back to
English Pod. My name is Marco and my name
is Catherine and today we're talking
about something we talk about every year.
Every year after Christmas or well
during the Christmas holidays we talk about
New Year's, New Year's Day and a very
important topic, New Year's Resolutions.
Alright, so we're not going to preview anything
today, it's all in the dialogue, but when we come back
we'll be talking more about what you hear and some
of the great phrases you can use at the New Year.
Did you read this? It says that the
number one New Year resolution
people make is to spend more
time with friends and family.
Why would that be funny? Well
think about it. We are a society that
is always on the go. Not because
we have to but because we want to.
Why? We work hard and spend less
time at home because we are trying to
provide for our family with goods
and services that are usually unnecessary.
I don't agree but
anyways, I think you should
start thinking of New
Year's resolution yourself.
What's the point? We always
make New Year's resolutions and
by February we will have
forgotten about them. It's pointless.
Well maybe then you should resolve
to stick into your goals and objectives.
What about you? Your gym
bag is gathering dust and you still
have brand new running shoes
that are yet to be jogged in.
Well I would go if you
catch your promise of going
to the gym with me every
day. Yeah, yeah, whatever.
Alright, great work back.
So this is very typical.
A New Year's resolution that you make but
then people don't really stick to it, etc.
You don't? Usually they
don't. Alright, but you're
probably wondering what
is a New Year's resolution.
So why don't we take a look at this word
and many more on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Okay,
so New Year's resolution let's
break this phrase down
the first phrase is New Year's.
So the New Year is January 1st
in the West and it is celebrated on
the 31st of December at night when
the clock changes to the New Year.
And a New Year's resolution
remember that S there is something that
you want to do or to change
in the New Year. It's a fresh start.
Okay, so you pretty much the verb that you
use there is to resolve to do something.
So my New Year's resolution
is to go to the gym every day.
It's like a promise to yourself. Right, so and
this is very common right among Americans they
try and because it's a New Year it's a fresh
start so they want to start doing something great.
Exactly, we can talk about
this at the end but a lot of
companies try to use this to
sell Americans stupid things.
So we'll get there in a minute but
the two people in this dialogue are
talking about the idea of spending
more time with friends and family.
And the other persons as well
sometimes it's hard to do that
because you have to provide
your family with goods and services.
All right.
This phrase goods and services
is very common especially
in economics and sociology.
So what does this mean?
Together right so goods are
tangible items things that you buy you
know like food or you know
clothes clothes a TV etc. stuff stuff.
And services of course are other
things like for example going
to the doctor or the dentist
or any other service you get.
So service usually includes another
person doing something for you.
But you might not actually get something
physical like a TV if you pay for it.
So goods and services it's included in
this phrase always goods and services.
Very good and well moving on as we
mentioned with the New Year's resolution
we had that verb there to resolve so
what does it mean if I want to resolve?
Okay well to resolve as we said is to decide
or to promise yourself to do something.
So it's a decision that you don't
want to change your mind about.
For example I this year I've
resolved to quit smoking that
means I've made a decision
for myself and I'm going to do it.
Okay very good strong and not to be confused with like to solve
right there has no no real relation there right. No resolve
to resolve to do something is to have a strong passion or
interest in doing something for yourself or changing an action.
Very good and well our last
word for language takeaway
is brand new a brand new
something that's brand new.
So buy a brand new car come down to Captain's car
lot. So brand new is something we hear a lot of
marketing it's also something that that well these
words just go together very often and something is new.
Okay you just bought
it or it just came out but
something brand new
is really fresh really new.
So brand new a brand new car a
brand new watch etc a brand new movie.
A brand new movie or brand yeah
brand new cereal how do you ever try it.
Very good so great phrases there very
good so great words there why don't
we listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back with three phrases.
Did you read this it says that the
number one new year resolution
people make is to spend more
time with friends and family.
Why would that be funny. Well
think about it we are society that
is always on the go not because
we have to but because we want to.
Why we work hard and spend less
time at home because we're trying to
provide for our family with goods
and services that are usually unnecessary.
I don't agree but
anyways I think you should
start thinking the new
year's resolution yourself.
What's the point we always
make new year's resolutions and
by February we will have
forgotten about them it's pointless.
Well maybe then you should resolve
to sticking to your goals and objectives.
What about you your gym bag
is gathering dust and you still
have brand new running shoes
that are yet to be jogged in.
Well I would go if you
kept your promise of going
to the gym with me every
day. Yeah yeah whatever.
Alright we're back so now let's take a look
at these three phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay this first phrase is
very common at gas stations
and food like fast food
chains when we say on the go.
Alright so he mentioned
that we are a society that
is always on the go. It
means we're always moving.
Exactly so you're always going
to work going home from work
going to the store going
to the school to get the kids.
Always moving moving
moving so that that kind
of action that kind
of life is on the go.
You can also say eat on the
go. That means I eat while I'm
going somewhere while I'm
doing something. I don't sit down.
Okay so on the go and we'll talking
about New Year's resolution and we say
that well many people resolve to do
something but they don't really do it.
And we have a phrase
that is used here to
stick to something.
Stick to your resolution.
To stick to it. So you think of tape or glue these things
that help things stick together. Okay so in that sense
it's kind of it's a way for you to describe continuing to
do something or not stopping, not quitting, not ending it.
So I could say remember how I
said I wanted to quit smoking?
Well I'm really going to stick to this
resolution because I think it's important.
That means I'm not going to give up. Right very good so
you're going to stay with it. You're not going to give
up. All right so stick to something like for example
our English there's they'll stick to learning English.
And we could say as a word
of it as words of encouragement
he's stick to it. Stick to it
don't give up. Don't give up.
All right and well finally they were
discussing more arguing about the gym
membership and everything and he mentioned
that the gym bag is gathering dust.
All right this is a very nice phrase I think because it's very
visual I like I like phrases where you can see what's happening. So
gathering means collecting that means that the dust in the air it's
building on this bag and something is gathering dust if we don't use it.
So we haven't gone to the gym because our bag is in the corner and
it's just filled with dust. Exactly we could also say this about
the computer. Why should I buy you a new computer Marco if you never
use the old one that's just sitting in the house gathering dust.
Very good. Okay so it's another way of
saying you never use it you never do it etc.
It's for an object though you
can't say you are gathering.
Well that'd be a little weird you
might be dead or. All right great
phrases so why don't we listen
to this dialogue one last time.
Did you read this? It says that
the number one new year resolution
people make is to spend more
time with friends and family.
Why would that be funny? Well
think about it we are a society that is
always on the go not because we
have to but because we want to. Why?
We work hard and spend less time at
home because we're trying to provide
for our family with goods and
services that are usually unnecessary.
I don't agree but
anyways I think you should
start thinking the new
year's resolution yourself.
What's the point? We always make new year's resolutions
and by February we will have forgotten about
them. It's pointless. Well maybe then you should
resolve to stick into your goals and objectives.
What about you? Your gym
bag is gathering dust and you still
have brand new running shoes
that are yet to be jogged in.
Well I would go if you
catch your promise of going
to the gym with me every
day. Yeah yeah whatever.
Alright we're back and well as you mentioned there are
some interesting things about this dialogue especially
when they talked about a society that is always on the go
and you mentioned that well sometimes you eat on the go.
And I've seen people in the United States
that are actually eating while driving.
I'm guilty of doing
that. We have no time to
actually sit down for
like 15 minutes and eat.
Now I remember being in high school at home
and you know you just have so much stuff
to do you have school then after school
there's like soccer practice after that.
There's music lessons and you never have time to
eat so you have to grab food in the car and then
on the way home you're picking things up and you
get home and you do your homework or whatever.
There's so much stuff to do
and it doesn't stop. It doesn't stop
when you grow up. It doesn't
stop if you're an older person.
And it's the way life is in America. Wow yeah that's really interesting because I
think many of our listeners that are in other countries would find that a little bit
peculiar if they actually went to the United States and saw somebody in their car
you know like having a hamburger while driving you know and sipping on their soda.
Yeah it's kind of sad. Well that's the thing you don't
have much time. But actually this is based on true
events kind of on the fact that many Americans do
want to spend more time at home with their friends.
With their family because as
you say you're always so busy.
And I think it's the nice
resolution to to resolve to
have dinner with your family
once or twice a week at home.
When you sit down and you talk about your lives
it's nice because you get to share and you get to
know each other better and you know otherwise
you're always just on the go in different places.
Yeah exactly. So we want to hear your
comments in your opinions about this topic.
So why don't you visit our website
englishpot.com and we'll see you guys there.
Don't forget to share with
us your New Year's resolutions.
Everyone's got one so I'm
very excited to hear those.
Alright. Until next time everyone. Bye.